A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers FA108
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office and Homes Files, 1928-1978 1955-1978; 3; 40 Cubic Feet 115 Boxes
  - Speeches, 1928-1978; 6
    - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies - Letters of Appreciation, October 4, 1964 (Box 89, Folder 704)
    - Macapagal (President of Philippines) Dinner, October 9, 1964 (Box 89, Folder 705)
    - General, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 706)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 707)
    - Japan Society, Sato Dinner, January 14, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 708)
    - English Language Education Council (Tokyo), Building Dedication, February 23, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 709)
    - Subsistence and Peasant Economics Conference, February 23, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 710)
    - Subsistence and Peasant Economics Conference, February 23, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 711)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, March 8, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 712)
    - "New York Herald Tribune," Author Luncheon, March 15, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 713)
    - Pell Committee, Testimony, March 18, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 714)
    - Concert Artists Guild, Award Dinner, April 15, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 715)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Dinner, May 5, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 716)
    - Japan America Society of Chicago, Dinner, May 13, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 717)
    - Japan America Society of Chicago, Dinner, May 13, 1965 (Box 90, Folder 718)
    - "Voice of America," Recording on Anniversary of Nehru's Death, May 25, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 719)
    - Population Council, June 10, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 720)
    - Arts Councils of America, June 17, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 721)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Staff Luncheon, June 24, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 722)
    - Foreign Aid Expenditures Subcommittee (Senate Government Operations Committee), July 28, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 723)
    - International Conference on Family Planning Programs, August 23, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 724)
    - "The City and the Arts", September 7, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 725)
    - Mikasa (Crown Prince of Japan), Introduction of, September 17, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 726)
    - United Negro College Fund, October 4, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 727)
    - Lincoln Center, Beaumont Theater Dedication, October 14, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 728)
    - Economic Club of New York, November 8, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 729)
    - Economic Club of New York, November 8, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 730)
    - White House Conference on Population, November 29, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 731)
    - Lincoln Center, Library and Museum of the Performing Arts Opening, November 30, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 732)
    - General, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 733)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 734)
    - Shastri (Prime Minister of India), Death of, January 11, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 735)
    - Lotos Club, January 27, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 736)
      - Lotos Club (Box P 171, Folder 37)
    - House Committee on Foreign Affairs, March 9, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 737)
    - Indira Gandhi (Prime Minister of India), March 31, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 738)
    - Lincoln Center, April 20, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 739)
    - Far East-America Council, May 17, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 740)
      - Far East-America Council (Box P 171, Folder 38)
    - Far East-America Council, May 17, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 741)
    - World Leaders Statement, July 21, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 742)
    - Metropolitan Opera House, September 1, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 743)
    - Metropolitan Opera House, Lehmbruck Sculpture Unveiling, September 6, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 744)
    - Metropolitan Opera House, Opening Night, September 16, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 745)
    - Emmons (West Virginia) Community Improvement Association, September 17, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 746)
    - Ferdinand Marcos (President of Philippines), September 20, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 747)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, September 21, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 748)
    - Shiina (Japanese Foreign Minister) and Fukuda (Japanese Finance Minister), Luncheon, September 23, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 749)
    - "The Greatest Challenge of Our Time," ("Reader's Digest" film), Introductory Remarks, October 14, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 750)
    - U Thant, World Leaders' Statement Release, December 10, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 751)
    - Taylor (Maurice W.), Dinner, April 11, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 752)
    - Concord Academy, April 17-18, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 753)
    - Asia Society, Dinner, May 16, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 754)
    - Ramon Magsaysay Center Building (Manila), Dedication, September 2, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 755)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, September 21, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 756)
    - Margaret Sanger Award, October 19, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 757)
    - "Parent's Magazine," Medal, November 14, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 758)
    - University of Michigan, Population Conference, November 16, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 759)
    - University of Michigan, Population Conference, November 16, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 760)
    - University of Michigan, Population Conference, November 16, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 761)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, November 28, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 762)
    - Rockefeller Public Service Awards, December 6, 1967 (Box 94, Folder 763)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, Symposium, April 2, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 764)
    - "Voice of America," Population Broadcast, June 5, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 765)
    - Family of Man Award, October 23, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 766)
    - Association for the Study of Abortion, November 18, 1968 (Box 94, Folder 767)
    - House Committee on Ways and Means, February 27, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 768)
    - Arts and Education Council of Greater St. Louis, April 17, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 769)
    - American Medical Association, July 15, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 770)
    - Senate Committee on Government Operations, September 15, 1969 (Box 94, Folder 771)
    - Senate Finance Committee, September 17, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 772)
    - Lincoln Center, Juilliard School Opening, October 26, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 773)
    - House Committee on Government Operations, Hearings to Establish a Commission on Population Growth and the American Future, November 19, 1969 (Box 95, Folder 774)
    - 1970 (Box 95, Folder 775)
    - 1971 (Box 95, Folder 776)
    - 1972 (Box 95, Folder 777)
    - Princeton University, September 1973 (Box 95, Folder 778)
    - 1974 (Box 95, Folder 779)
    - 1975 (Box 95, Folder 780)
    - 1976 (Box 95, Folder 781)
    - 1977 (Box 95, Folder 782)
    - 1978 (Box 95, Folder 783)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book I (Box 96, Folder 784)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book I (Box 96, Folder 785)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book II (Box 96, Folder 786)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book II (Box 96, Folder 787)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book III (Box 96, Folder 788)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book III (Box 96, Folder 789)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book IV (Box 97, Folder 790)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book IV (Box 97, Folder 791)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book V (Box 97, Folder 792)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book V (Box 97, Folder 793)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VI (Box 97, Folder 794)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VI (Box 97, Folder 795)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VI (Box 97, Folder 796)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VI (Box 97, Folder 797)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VII (Box 98, Folder 798)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VII (Box 98, Folder 799)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VIII (Box 98, Folder 800)
    - Speeches, Remarks,and Releases - Book VIII (Box 98, Folder 801)
  - Trips, 1958-1971, 1976; 7
    Arranged chronologically. Background material on countries visited by Rockefeller is arranged alphabetically and is filed at the end of this subseries.
    This subseries is a continuation of the travel records in series 1, subseries 6 and series 2. It includes the notebooks and diaries from Rockefeller's almost-annual visits to Asia.
    - Asia (Winter 1962) - Book 1 (Box 99, Folder 802)
    - Asia (Winter 1962) - Book 2 (Box 99, Folder 803)
    - Asia (Winter 1962) - Book 3 (Box 99, Folder 804)
    - Asia (Winter 1962) - Diaries and Notes (Box 99, Folder 805)
    - Europe (Summer 1962) - Diary (Box 99, Folder 806)
    - Asia (Winter 1963) (Box 99, Folder 807)
    - Asia (Winter 1963) - Diaries and Notes (Box 99, Folder 808)
    - England and Kenya (Summer 1963) (Box 99, Folder 809)
    - England and Kenya (Summer 1963) - Diary (Box 99, Folder 810)
    - Colombia (February 1964) - Diary (Box 99, Folder 811)
    - Europe (Summer 1964) - Diary (Box 99, Folder 812)
    - Asia (Winter 1965) - Book 1 (Box 99, Folder 813)
    - Asia (Winter 1965) - Book 2 (Box 99, Folder 814)
    - Asia (Winter 1965) - Diaries and Notes (Box 100, Folder 815)
    - North Africa and Middle East (Winter 1966) (Box 100, Folder 816)
    - North Africa and Middle East (Winter 1966) - Diary and Notes (Box 100, Folder 817)
    - Europe and Asia (Summer 1966) - Book 1 (Box 100, Folder 818)
    - Europe and Asia (Summer 1966) - Book 2 (Box 100, Folder 819)
    - Europe and Asia (Summer 1966) - Diaries and Observations (Box 100, Folder 820)
    - South America (October-November 1966) (Box 100, Folder 821)
    - South America (October-November 1966) - Diary and Notes (Box 100, Folder 822)
    - Mexico (May 1967) (Box 100, Folder 823)
    - Mexico (May 1967) - Diary (Box 100, Folder 824)
    - Asia (Summer 1967) (Box 100, Folder 825)
    - Asia (Summer 1967) - Diary and Notes (Box 100, Folder 826)
    - Near East and Europe (Winter 1968) (Box 101, Folder 827)
    - Near East and Europe (Winter 1968) - Diary and Notes (Box 101, Folder 828)
    - Italy (April 1970) (Box 101, Folder 829)
    - Philippines and Japan (Spring 1970) (Box 101, Folder 830)
    - Japan and Taiwan (May 1971) (Box 101, Folder 831)
    - Japan and Korea (January 1976) (Box 101, Folder 832)
    - Background Material - Afghanistan, 1962-1963 (Box 101, Folder 833)
    - Background Material - Burma, 1962, 1963 (Box 101, Folder 834)
    - Background Material - Cambodia, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 835)
    - Background Material - Ceylon, 1960 (Box 101, Folder 836)
    - Background Material - Formosa, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 837)
    - Background Material - Hong Kong, 1958-1961 (Box 101, Folder 838)
    - Background Material - India, 1954-1959, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 839)
    - Background Material - Indonesia, 1957-1962 (Box 101, Folder 840)
    - Background Material - Japan, 1958-1965 (Box 101, Folder 841)
    - Background Material - Laos, 1960, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 842)
    - Background Material - Malaya, 1959, 1961, n.d. (Box 101, Folder 843)
    - Background Material - Nepal, 1960 (Box 101, Folder 844)
    - Background Material - Pakistan, 1958, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 845)
    - Background Material - Philippines, 1958-1962 (Box 101, Folder 846)
    - Background Material - Thailand, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 847)
    - Background Material - Vietnam, 1962 (Box 101, Folder 848)
  - Subject File, 1936-1978; 8
    Arranged alphabetically by subject
    This eclectic subseries contains information on a wide range of topics, including public relations, staff, and foreign relations. Of note is the typescript of the autobiography of Frederick T. Gates, "Chapters in My Life," which was given to Rockefeller by Gates's granddaughter, Janet Gates Bonney. Also found here are copies of Rockefeller's oral history interviews with Columbia University as well as reactions to publication of "The Rockefellers: An American Dynasty" by Peter Collier and David Horowitz. This subseries contains the printed journal from the United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration conference in 1943, to which Rockefeller was a Navy Department representative. Records of the Rockefeller Brothers, Inc., a venture capital operation, are also housed here.
    - Articles and Interviews with John Davison Rockefeller 3rd, 1956-1978 (Box 102, Folder 849)
    - Articles and Interviews with John Davison Rockefeller 3rd - Film and Television, 1972-1977 (Box 102, Folder 850)
    - Articles and Interviews with John Davison Rockefeller 3rd - "Time" Magazine, 1966 (Box 102, Folder 851)
    - Defense Departement, U.S., 1952-1961 (Box 102, Folder 852)
    - Dulles (John Foster) Oral History Project, 1965 (Box 102, Folder 853)
    - Foreign Relations - Background Material, 1955-1960 (Box 102, Folder 854)
    - Foreign Relations - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1966 (Box 102, Folder 855)
    - Gates, F. T., "Chapters of My Life," Typescript, 1928 (Box 102, Folder 856)
    - Gates, F. T., "Chapters of My Life," Typescript, 1928 (Box 102, Folder 857)
    - Gates, F. T., "Chapters of My Life," Typescript, 1928 (Box 102, Folder 858)
    - Greenfield Village, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 859)
    - Ladejinsky, Wolf - Vietnam Years (Vol. 3), 1955-1961 (Box 103, Folder 860)
    - Ladejinsky, Wolf - Ford Foundation Years (Vol. 4), 1961-1964 (Box 103, Folder 861)
    - Ongoing Responsibilities and Interests, 1966-1977 (Box 103, Folder 862)
    - Printed Material, 1940-1946 (Box 103, Folder 863)
    - Public Relations, 1953, 1964-1977 (Box 104, Folder 864)
    - Public Relations - Rosenberg, Anna M., 1950 (Box 104, Folder 865)
    - Public Relations - Ruder and Finn, 1968-1976 (Box 104, Folder 866)
    - "Reminiscences of John D. Rockefeller 3rd," Columbia University Oral History, Part I, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 867)
    - "Reminiscences of John D. Rockefeller 3rd," Columbia University Oral History, Part I, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 868)
    - "Reminiscences of John D. Rockefeller 3rd," Columbia University Oral History, Part I, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 869)
    - "Reminiscences of John D. Rockefeller 3rd," Columbia University Oral History, Part I, 1964 (Box 104, Folder 870)
    - "Reminiscences of John D. Rockefeller 3rd," Columbia University Oral History, Part II, 1970 (Box 105, Folder 871)
    - "The Rockefellers: An American Dynasty" (Collier and Horowitz), 1976 (Box 105, Folder 872)
    - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. - General Papers, 1955-1962 (Box 105, Folder 873)
    - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. - Legal Papers, 1946 (Box 105, Folder 874)
    - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. - Organization and Procedures, 1947, 1948, 1951 (Box 105, Folder 875)
    - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. - Report to Directors, June 30, 1958 (Box 105, Folder 876)
    - Rockefeller Brothers, Inc. - Tax Issues, 1946-1947 (Box 105, Folder 877)
    - Rockefeller Center, Inc., 1936-1957, 1959-1963, c1972 (Box 105, Folder 878)
    - Rockefeller Center, Inc., 1936-1957, 1959-1963, c1972 (Box 105, Folder 879)
    - Staff - Applications for Employment (CLOSED FOLDER), 1951 (Box 106A, Folder 880)
    - Staff - Employees (CLOSED FOLDER), 1941-1960 (Box 106A, Folder 881)
    - Staff - Employees - One Beekman Place (CLOSED FOLDER), 1967-1974 (Box 106A, Folder 882)
    - Staff - Employees - Pocantico Hills (CLOSED FOLDER), 1940-1941, 1946, 1956, 1959 (Box 106A, Folder 883)
    - Staff - Group Insurance and Pensions (CLOSED FOLDER), 1938-1961 (Box 106A, Folder 884)
    - Staff - Meeting Agendas and Summaries, 1964-1978 (Box 106A, Folder 885)
    - Staff - Policy and Planning Committee Status Reports, 1954-1959 (Box 106A, Folder 0886A)
    - Staff - Policy and Planning Committee Status Reports, 1960-1964 (Box 106B, Folder 0886B)
    - Staff - Salaries (CLOSED FOLDER), 1937-1946 (Box 106B, Folder 887)
    - Standard Oil of California - Project Standard Oil (CLOSED FOLDER), 1970, 1973 (Box 106B, Folder 888)
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, Journal of First Session of the Council, 1943 (Box 107, Folder 0888A)
  - Financial Material, 1962-1978; 9
    This subseries, which is a continuation of the financial records in series 1, subseries 7, contains the annual reports of Rockefeller's charitable giving.
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 889)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 890)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 891)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 892)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 893)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 894)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 895)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 896)
    - Contributions - Program, 1962-1970 (Box 108, Folder 897)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 898)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 899)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 900)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 901)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 902)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 903)
    - Contributions - Program, 1971-1976 (Box 109, Folder 904)
    - Contributions - Program, 1977-1978 (Box 110, Folder 905)
    - Contributions - Program, 1977-1978 (Box 110, Folder 906)
    - Contributions - Nondeductible, 1976-1978 (Box 110, Folder 907)
    - Contributions - Reports, 1962-1978 (Box 110, Folder 908)
    - Contributions - Reports, 1962-1978 (Box 110, Folder 909)
    - Contributions - Reports, 1962-1978 (Box 110, Folder 910)
  - JDR 3rd Material Donated by William P. Garrison, 1906-1929; 10
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Donated to the RAC in January 2008 by the family of William P. Garrison.
    Biographical / Historical
    William P. Garrison was the farm manager at Fieldwood Farm from 1981-1985.
    - Princeton Commencement Book, 1929 (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - JDR 3rd passport, 1926-1927 (Box 115, Folder 2)
    - JDR 3rd Infant notebook, 1906-1917 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Documents feedings, height and weight
- Audiovisual materials, 4
  When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
  If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
  - Episode of NewsFront: Segment with John D. Rockefeller, 1967 December 16 (Reel III 14.1 Ff 49)
    All inquires to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    Television news programs; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978
  - Asian Art Collection, 1970 (Reel AV 1113)
    Footage from the opening of the JDR 3rd Asian Art Collection at the Asia Society. JDR 3rd and wife Blanchette are in attendance.
    Art collections; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978; Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker; Asia Society
  - Bicentennial: Beyond the Birthday, 1975 (Reel AV 1945)
    Film about the projects and ideas generated around the Bicentennial. Introduced by President Ford, the film features interviews with prominent figures and examines civic projects all looking to examine the history of the US so far, and to make constructive plans for the future. Interviews with JDR 3rd, Ladybird Johnson, Dr. Jonas Salk, and others.
    United States--History; Ford, Gerald R.; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978; Salk, Jonas
  - Frontiers of Faith, 1952 (Reel AV 1713)
    NBC presentation: panel discussion about Christian ministry and religion in America with JDR 3rd (as president of the RBF, the RBF Fund for Theological Education began in 1952); panel includes Eugene Carson Blake (moderator), Liston Pope, Ralph Sockman, Nathan Pusey.
    File Plan
    III 14.4-10
    Religion; Clergy--Office; United States; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1952 (Reel AV 1108)
    Compilation of newsreel footage from 1952: King and Queen of Jordan visit to Madrid; JDR 3rd gives speech in Japan & visits International Culture Center; viewing British helicopters in England.
    III 14.4-9
    Newsreels; Japan; Spain; England; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Helicopters; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd: Population Explosion, 1967 (Reel AV 1652)
    From an ABC interview, a short statement from JDR 3rd on the realities of family planning in response to the question, "What is the scope of the problem of the population explosion?"
    III 14.4-15
    Family planning; Filmed interviews; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Lecture, 1973 October 31 (Reel AV 1864)
    Speech by JDR 3rd about the U.S. Bicentennial (1976), the current state of the nation, and remembering his recently deceased brother, Winthrop. Introduced by his nephew, Winthrop P. Rockefeller, who pays tribute to his father and the Rockefeller Family. Filmed at the University of Arizona six months after the death of Winthrop A. Rockefeller.
    III 14 F60
    Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Winthrop Paul; Rockefeller family; University of Arizona
  - JDR IV Campaign in West Virginia, 1966 (Reel AV 110, Box 1, Dvd 110)
    Report on JDR IV campaign for West Virginia seat in House of Delegates, reported by Paul Duke of NBC.
    III 14 F2
    West Virginia; Political campaigns -- United States; Rockefeller, John D., IV (John Davison)
  - Kaleidoscope Interview with JDR 3rd, 1969 April 30 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1390, Dvd AV 1325, Reel AV 1325)
    JDR 3rd interviewed by James Day about the realities and responsibilities of being a Rockefeller. Questions: Was there a spirit of competition between the brothers? Were you groomed for philanthropic responsibility? What pursuit has given you the most satisfaction? What is your rationale for giving?
    III 14.4-11
    Filmed interviews; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978
  - Lincoln Center Opening, 1963 (Reel AV 1704)
    Lincoln Center NY: construction; opening of first units; views of interior; visits with JDR 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Jacob Javits, Jacqueline Kennedy.
    III 14.5-12
    Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 904-1986; Kennedy, Jacqueline Bouvier, 1929-1994
  - National Conference on Citizenship, 1970 (Reel AV 109)
    Coverage of bipartisan workshop on student involvement with the electoral process, informal panel discussions-film funded with grants from the Stern Foundation and JDR 3rd.
    III 14 F1
  - Pilgrimage to Virginia, 1946 March 8 (Reel AV 1117)
    Winston Churchill visits Virginia with his wife and daughter: speech at the Virginia General Assembly in Richmond with General Eisenhower and Governor William Tuck; visit to Colonial Williamsburg with JDR 3rd, Kenneth Chorley, and General Eisenhower.
    Virginia; Churchill, Winston; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight D.); Tuck, William M. (William Munford), 1896-1983; Rockefeller, John D. 3rd (John Davison), 1906-1978; Chorley, Kenneth; Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.)
  - Population and the American Future, Part I, 1972 (Reel AV 1712, Reel AV 1711)
    Overview of findings from 2-year research project on population growth funded by JDR III, Ford Foundation, Commonwealth Fund, Xerox Corp, and the Scaife Family Fund. Part I: change in life expectancy, population growth statistics, environmental deterioration, national security, illegal immigration, urban development, national distribution policy.
    III 14.4-2 (AV 1711) and III 14.4-3 (AV 1712)
    Population; Public health; Sexual health; Sex instruction; Population and Population Control; Abortion
  - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1958 (Reel AV 1017)